<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aegisub Docs on</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Aegisub Docs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><atom:link href="https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Main Page</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/main_page/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/main_page/</guid><description>Welcome to the Aegisub manual. See our about page for more information on the program, or browse the topics on the left bar.
Documentation related to delopment of Aegisub and building Aegisub is located at the bug tracker.
Starting points Quick overview of Aegisub
Common tasks:
Timing a translated script to audio Basic typesetting of on-screen signs Putting your finished subtitles onto the video (for viewing or distribution) ^</description></item><item><title>What is Aegisub?</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/about/</guid><description>Aegisub was originally created as a tool to make typesetting, particularly in anime fansubs, a less painful experience. At the time of the start of the project, many other programs that supported the Advanced Substation Alpha format lacked (and in many cases, still lack; development on several competing programs have since been dropped for various reasons completely unrelated to Aegisub) many vital functions, or were too buggy and/or unreliable to be really useful.</description></item><item><title>Highlights</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/highlights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/highlights/</guid><description>Some highlights of Aegisub:
Simple and intuitive yet powerful interface for editing subtitles With help from such features as spell checking/thesaurus, a translation assistant, call tips for override tags, syntax highlighting and various macros, translating, editing and quality assuring subtitles is now easier than ever. Made a mistake? Had a system crash? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, Aegisub saves your .ass with features like multi-level undo/redo, auto saving, backups and emergency recovery saving in case of system or program crashes.</description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/credits/</guid><description>Aegisub was originally written by Rodrigo Braz Monteiro with significant contributions from Niels Martin Hansen. Development was lead by Monteiro through 2008, Hansen through 2010, and by Thomas Goyne from 2011 onward.
Programming Main Programmers:
Rodrigo Braz Monteiro (ArchMage ZeratuL) - Lead developer, video system, audio system, subtitles I/O, tools Niels Martin Hansen (jfs) - Automation, Lua automation, audio system, tools Thomas Goyne (Plorkyeran) - Lead developer for 3.</description></item><item><title>Support Aegisub</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/support/</guid><description>Do you want to support Aegisub? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s easy!
Feedback You can give us feedback - comments, critiques, suggestions, etc. Bug reports and feature requests are always welcome. Check out our forums and the bug tracker, or stop by for a chat in the IRC channel.
Spreading the word Like Aegisub? Tell your friends about it! Spreading the word is a good way of helping Aegisub to be the best subtitle editor around.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/faq/</guid><description>A small collection of Frequently Asked Questions about Aegisub - mostly stuff that didn&amp;rsquo;t fit anywhere else.
Karaoke effects? See the Karaoke Templater tutorials.
Can I create DVD subtitles with Aegisub? Not directly, but there&amp;rsquo;s a nifty program called MaestroSBT that can convert SSA to VOBSubs. It does have quite a bunch of restrictions on what tags and other things may be used, so reading its manual first is advised. Also note that it does not accept ASS - only SSA.</description></item><item><title>Tutorials</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/tutorials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/tutorials/</guid><description>The following tutorials are available for Aegisub:
Video Tutorials (Screencasts) Dialogue Timing Description: A video describing how to time using Aegisub.
By: Karl Blomster
Link: http://mod16.org/aegisub/timingtutorialimprovisation.mkv
Description: A video showing an experienced user timing at full speed in Aegisub.
By: Karl Blomster
Link: http://mod16.org/aegisub/timing-fullspeed.mkv
Kanji Timer Description: A video tutorial demonstrating how the kanji timer can be used to synchronize kanji timing to romaji timing.</description></item><item><title>Editing Subtitles</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/editing_subtitles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/editing_subtitles/</guid><description>Editing subtitles is what Aegisub is made for. This page will deal with basic text editing of subtitle lines; for more information on the typography of subtitles, see typesetting. For information on the timing of subtitle lines, see working with audio.
Opening subtitles In the File menu, there are four menu choices that relate to opening or creating subtitles:
New subtitles Create a new, blank script (i.e. close the current file).</description></item><item><title>Exporting Subtitles</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/exporting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/exporting/</guid><description>In addition to the normal &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Save as&amp;rdquo; functions, Aegisub also has an &amp;ldquo;Export&amp;rdquo; feature, which can transform the entire script through various export filters. This is used for a number of things ranging from framerate conversions over karaoke effect generation to just saving to other formats and/or character sets.
The export dialog {: class=&amp;ldquo;center&amp;rdquo;}
The upper half of the window contains the available filters. Ticking one or more of them will apply them in the order they are listed; use the move up/down buttons to change the order.</description></item><item><title>Applying Subtitles</title><link>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/attaching_subtitles_to_video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aeg-dev.github.io/AegiSite/zh-cn/docs/3.2/attaching_subtitles_to_video/</guid><description>In digital encoding, there are two main ways of including subtitles in a video: softsubbing and hardsubbing. Both methods has unique advantages and disadvantages, along with various arguments both for and against each method.
Hardsubbing Hardsubbing is a method that &amp;ldquo;burns in&amp;rdquo; subtitles into the actual video portion of a movie. Digital hardsubs are much like subtitled VHS tapes; the subtitles cannot be turned off.
Advantages of Hardsubbing Hardsubbing is usually much less demanding on the playback device.</description></item></channel></rss>